Guide to the Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Collection, 1973-1998 AIS.2002.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Financial Files, 1979-1993; II.
  This series contains files relating to the finances of the MVUC, primarily from 1979 to 1993 and is arranged chronologically. Since the MVUC is a non-profit organization that relies on grants and private donations for their funding, this series includes documents on grant proposals, donations and audits. The MVUC received most of their funding from a renewable grant by Campaign for Human Development (CHD). This series contains files on how the organization applied for, received, and maintained their CHD grant. Also included in the series are documents pertaining to individual and corporate donations to the MVUC through the United Way of Pittsburgh.
  - Mortgage Help, undated (Oversize 1, Folder 14)
  - Film Project Proposal Local Building Project, undated (Oversize 1, Folder 15)
  - Mortgage Information, 1979-1982 (Oversize 1, Folder 16)
  - Discount Foundation's Grant to MVUC, December 1982 (Oversize 1, Folder 17)
  - Curry Fund, February 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 18)
  - Westinghouse's Grant to MVUC, October 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 19)
  - Ledger Code, October 1, 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 20)
  - Video Grants Project, November 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 21)
  - Mellon Fund, December 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 22)
  - Money Raised by MVUC, 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 23)
  - Heinz Foundation Grant to MVUC, 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 24)
  - The Pittsburgh Non-Profit Sector in a Time of Government Retrenchment, 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 25)
  - CHD Correspondence and 1983 Grant Agreement (Oversize 1, Folder 26-28)
  - United Way Donor Option (MVUC), 1983 (Oversize 1, Folder 29)
  - Fiscal Year 1983 Budget Review (Oversize 1, Folder 30)
  - CHD 1st Quarter Report, September 1983-August 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 31)
  - Local Initiatives Support Coalition (LISC) Pittsburgh Two-Year Report, September 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 32)
  - $190,000,000 Bond Issue, October 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 33)
  - Grant Proposals: Need more Fund/CHD, December 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 34)
  - Expenses, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 35)
  - 1984 CHD "Project Outreach" Proposal (Oversize 1, Folder 36)
  - CHD Grant Drafts, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 37-38)
  - United Way Contributions, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 39)
  - Villers Foundation Grant, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 40)
  - Proposal to the Pittsburgh Foundation, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 41)
  - Funding Correspondences, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 42)
  - Grant Information, 1984 (Oversize 1, Folder 43)
  - Fiscal year 1984 Payroll Expenses (Oversize 1, Folder 44)
  - CHD Implementation Draft, 1984-1985 (Oversize 1, Folder 45)
  - Balance Sheet, 1984-1985 (Oversize 1, Folder 46)
  - Fiscal Year 1985 Big Ledger Book (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CHD 1985 Updater, January 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Economic Dislocation and Unemployment Proposal Form, March 1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Health Project Interim Report, July 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1985 CHD Grant Agreement (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - P.S.A. Donor Option, September 19, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Finance and Administrative Committee, October 3, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) PA Funds, Winter 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - United Way Donor Option Campaign, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Income Tax Exemption, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1985 Budget Recap (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Contributors, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Utilities Campaign, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Financial Statements, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - United Way Donor Option, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - CHD Final Report 1984-1985, December 1985 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Audits, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1985 CHD Grant Proposals (Box 7, Folder 18-20)
  - Efforts at Health Care, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - NAA Regulations, Certification, Proposals, Etc., 1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - CHD Proposal, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - CHD Quarter Report, November 1985-January 1986 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Audit, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Balance Sheet, May 5, 1986, June 1, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - Income Tax, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Dollar Energy Fund, October 1986-December 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Corry Proposal, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Financial Statements, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Budget Postmortem, July 3, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Activities, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Donor Option Correspondences, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - United Way Correspondences, September-October 1987 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - USPC Budget, December 4, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - MMVUC Economic Revitalization Program -Community & Economic Development Fund Project Application, December, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Financial Statements, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Allegheny County Proposals, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Pittsburgh Foundation Proposal, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Petty Cash Records, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Tax Exemption, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Balance Sheet, September 1988, October-December 1989 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Combined Federal Campaign Application, April 26, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Price-Waterhouse Audit, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1990 Funding Application (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1990 Activity Report (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Audit, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Monthly Financial Report, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grants, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1992 Budget (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Welfare Lien Donations, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Governor's Task Force Travel Expenses, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - CHD Chronology, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Mon Valley Unemployed Legislative Files, 1979-1998; III.
  This series contains documents relating to the MVUC's lobbying efforts from 1982 to 1998 with reference material the dates back to 1979 and is arranged chronologically. Initially, the MVUC focused its lobbying efforts to rallies in downtown Pittsburgh to protest mill closures, job outsourcing, and sparse unemployment benefits. Overtime they began to take trips to Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, and Washington, D.C., to protest welfare liens (CRWL), insufficient Trade Adjustment Assistance (TRA) and Trade Readjustment Assistance (TRA), Low Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP), the Pennsylvania House Financing Agency (PHFA), and the Homeowners Emergency Mortgage Assistance Program (HEMAP). This series contains Barney Oursler's and Paul Lodico's notes on organizing protest, MVUC members congressional testimony, correspondence between the MVUC and state legislators, and TAA/TRA members decisions and appeals.
  - Study of Costs for Lien Repeal, December 17, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Welfare Lien and the tax Collapse, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Public Welfare Literature, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Pre-1988 TRA Appeal Information, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Thornfare Legislation, May 25, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Karnay, John Unemployment Compensation Appeal Decision, June 28, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Welfare Lien Information, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Pollution Control/Clean Air Act, United Steelworkers of America, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - US Senate Hearing, S. 2227, June 1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - H.R. Emergency Jobs Creation Bill, Res. 514, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Unemployment Compensation, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - March for Jobs and Justice Photographs, May 12, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - McKeesport March and Rally Photographs, October 6, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Sheriff Sale-Gold Room Photographs, November 1, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Legislation, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Legislative Correspondences, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Washington Lobbying Leaflets, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Mortgage Letters, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - March 15 Trip to DC Endorsements, January-February 1983 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - March 15 DC Notes, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - NUN Early Stuff, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Emergency Housing Assistance Act, February 1983 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Mortgage Legislative Committee, February 1983 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - US Steel Corp TRA Re-Certification, February 25, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - MVUC Harrisburg Testimony, March 1983 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Mortgage Committee Testimony House Committee VA Affairs, April 21, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Job Training Partnership Act, April 19, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Equity Protection Act Lobbying, May 16, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Butler County Welfare Hearings, May 19, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Iron City Legal Assistance Workers, May 27, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Council Endorsements, July 27, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Definition and Measurement of Unemployment, August 9, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Price vs. Cohen, September 13, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Allegheny County Sheriff's Sale, September 15, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Report on the Status of Unemployed Insurance, October 28, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Speak Out Against Utilities Shut-Off Campaign, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Legislative Action Committee, May 1983 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Philadelphia Unemployment Project Strategy Notes, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - NUN Organizing Notes, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 50-53)
  - March on Washington, D.C., 1983 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - TAA/TRA Lobby Trip To Harrisburg, October 7, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Discussion Papers from Seminar on Structural Unemployment and the New Perspectives on the Social Meaning of Work, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Materials from Seminar on Structural Unemployment and the New Perspectives on the Social Meaning of Work, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Utility Petitions, December 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Denominational Ministries Strategy, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5-7)
  - Union Movement from Structural Unemployment, Article by Barney Oursler, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - March 15 Endorsements (Outside Pittsburgh Area), February-March 1983 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Foreclosure Relief Information, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - National Day of Action Rally, July 27, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Washington Trip, May 15, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Churches and Community Endorsements, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - March on Washington, August 27, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - House of Representatives Hearing Testimony, September 15, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Harrisburg Hearings, September 27, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - DC Lobbying Trip, October 18, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - US Government Correspondences, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Sheriff Coon's Statement before the House of Representatives, February 22, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Utility Shut-Off Campaign, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Caliguiri Testimony before International Trade Commission, May 9-June 21 1984 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - MVUC Need for Emergency Housing Testimony, August 21, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - MVUC Testimony before House Committee on Ways and Means, September 12, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - History of "First Friday", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - MVUC Legal Services, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Unemployment Legislation, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - First Friday Information, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
  - Memorandum in Support of Claimant's Applications for TRA, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - "A Cry for Leadership" Economic Development, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Laying the Foundation for a Community based Job Development Project", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Comeback Conference Notes, July-October 1984 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Principles for Economic Recovery in Southwestern PA, September 1984 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Comeback Conference, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - Regional Utility Campaign, Fall 1984 (Box 9, Folder 36-40)
  - April 4th, Travel to Washington DC, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Lobbying in D.C., April 4, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - MVUC Facts, Literature, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Workshop on Advanced Community Organizing Notes, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Project Application to the Pittsburgh Foundation, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - NUN Notes, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Survey to Determine True Number of the Mon Valley Unemployed, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Legislation Information, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - TRA Information, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - People's Hearing and Lobbying Session, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - First Friday Information, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Testimony of Washington, D.C. Hearings, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Economic Growth and Revitalization Report, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Information Packet "From the Poor to the Pentagon", 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Legislative Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Research on Unemployment Insurance since 1979, January 14, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - List of People Attending Rally, March 4, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Report on "First Friday" Events, March 8, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Keep Federal Supplementation Compensation (FSC) Lobbying Efforts, March 8-20, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Washington, D.C. March for Peace, Jobs and Justice, April 20, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Testimony before the ADHOC Sub-Committee, May 2, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Testimony before House of Representatives Select Committee on Aging, July 24, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Testimony LIHEAP, September 18, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - UI Campaign Media, Correspondences, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Center for Popular Economics, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Federal Supplemental Compensation Campaign, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Employment in America: Illusory Recovery in a Decade of Decline," By the Full Employment Action Council, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - NUN, Fall 1984-Winter 1985 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - NUN, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 26-32)
  - Unemployment Compensation Legislation, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 33-38)
  - NUN, post February 1985 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Rally in Washington, D.C., 1985 (Box 10, Folder 40-41)
  - Ecumenical Great Lakes/ Appalachian Project (GLAP) Steering Committee, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 42-43)
  - Campaign for Human Development Proposal, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Materials from the Regional Reindustrialization Conference, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Testimony before the Committee on Aging, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Duquesne Press Conference Photographs, August 12, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rick Pomponic for House Select Committee on Aging Photographs, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Unemployment Compensation under Reagan Research, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - TAA/TRA USS Johnstown, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - TAA/TRA Information, Drafts, Correspondences, Appeals, Training, Certification, 1985-1990 (Box 11, Folder 7-73)
  - TAA/TRA Information, Drafts, Correspondences, Appeals, Training, Certification, 1985-1990 (Box 12, Folder 1-48)
  - MVUC Allocations in the Governor's 1986-1987 Budget, March 7, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - LIHEAP Testimonies, March 7, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Gramm-Rudman Cutbacks Symposium, April 21, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Venture Capital Fund, July 8, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - LIHEAP Testimony, August 8, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Dublin-Pittsburgh Research and Demonstration Project on Youth Unemployment, October-November 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - TRA: "New Ideas for an Old Problem", 1986 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Set Testimony-Monessa, Aliquippa, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
  - TRA Hearing Schedules, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Steel Labor Magazine, "USX: New Name, Worker Confrontation Braddock, PA, July-August 1986 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Information form the Pittsburgh Peace Institute, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - PA Department of Labor and Industry, September 1986 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Resources for a Home-Grown Economy, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - 40th Anniversary Symposium, Employment Act of 1946, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Trouble in Electric Valley River Communities Project, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Unemployed Council of Southwestern PA, TAA/TRA Correspondence and Project Proposal, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - UPCW Economic Dislocation Manual, January 20, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - TRA Board of Review Case, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Report on the Impact of the Unemployed Council of Southwestern Pennsylvania (UCSP) on the Region's Economy, August 5, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - TAA/TRA Working Group DC Trip, July 17, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - TRA Information, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 22-23)
  - Legislative Correspondences, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - TAA in Washington, D.C. Information, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Helpline Research, "On-Line With Helpline" Magazine, Winter 1987 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - TRA Photographs, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - TAA/TRA Improvements, Issues, Solutions, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Act 91/Hemap Appointments, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Establishment of Human Service Provider Councils in the Mon Valley, January 5, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Governor's Report on Job Training, March 1988 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Unemployment Compensation Board of review, May 25, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Proposed Rules Implementing 1988 TAA Amendment, December 21, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Dislocated Workers Program, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - USCP TRAA-TAA Campaign Update, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Welfare Lien Stationary, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - TAA Information, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 37-39)
  - TRA Appeals, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - General Analysis of Welfare Liens, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Unemployed Council Press Releases, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Jakiela TAA/TRA Benefits Denial Appeals, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Establishment of TRA Eligibility Periods under Trade Act, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Welfare Lien/CRWL Fact Sheet, Reports, Correspondences, Endorsements, 1989-1992 (Box 13, Folder 45-67)
  - Welfare Lien/CRWL Fact Sheet, Reports, Correspondences, Endorsements, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 1-14)
  - CRWL List, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - CRWL Homeowners Meetings, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Harrisburg Meeting Attendees, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - House Bill 223 Fiscal Notes, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - CRWL Washington County Meetings, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - CRWL Harrisburg Trip, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Welfare Liens Articles, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - CRWL Correspondences and Endorsements, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - CRWL Information Fair "Info on Liens", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - CRWL Union Contributors, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Bus Trip to Harrisburg, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Legislative Correspondences, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - CRWL Core Activists, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - CRWL Harrisburg Lobbying Trip, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - CRWL Butler County, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - CRWL House Bill 1131, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Campaign to Remove the Welfare Lien Action List, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Welfare Lien Questionnaires, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - CRWL Allegheny County Help Lists, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - CRWL Southern Counties Coordinators Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Washington County Lien Resolution, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - CRWL Delaware County "Problem Meeting", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - CRWL Delaware County "Don't Lien on My Dream", 1992 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - CRWL Allegheny County Homeowner's Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - CRWL Mercer County Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Harrisburg Lobbying Trip, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - CRWL Erie County Correspondences, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Leaflets for Welfare Liens, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Welfare Lien Fact Sheets, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Union and Church CRWL Endorsements, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Union and Business CRWL Endorsements, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - CWRL Pennsylvania Coordinators'Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - CRWL Delaware County Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - CRWL Lanedonne Meeting, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Lien Lobby List Volunteers, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Welfare Lien Lists, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Pittsburgh City Council Recognition of CRWL, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - CRWL Dauphin County Homeowners Meeting, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - CRWL Senate Vote, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - CRWL Implementation Questionnaires, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - CRWL Phone Pledges, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - CWRL Lien Removal Costs, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - CWRL Union Resolutions, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous Legislative Correspondences, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Unemployment Compensation Board of Review, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Governor's Task Force to Reduce Welfare Dependency, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 60-63)
  - Child Support Workshop, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - CRWL House of Representatives Notes, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lien List, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Credit Bureau Correspondences, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - TAA Referee Hearings, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Maple Creek UMMA Case Preparation (TAA/TRA), 1994 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Armbrust Order, Pennsylvania Department of Labor and Industry, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Kennedy Minimum Wage Forum, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Minimum Wage Literature, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Minimum Wage Campaign Strategy, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Campaign to Help Raise Minimum Wage, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Minimum Wage Campaign, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - TAA/TRA Appeals, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Turtle Creek and Butler County TAA/TRA, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - NAFTR/TAA Regulations, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Job Training Reform, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - National Commission for Employment Policy, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - "Careers Act", 1995 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Middle Class Bill of Rights, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - "Real Welfare Reform: Visions for Ending Poverty", 1995 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - "America Needs a Raise," Pittsburgh Town Meeting, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Minimum Wage Lobbying Trip, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Minimum Wage Senate Vote, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - CARC Report Information, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Welfare Lien Flyers, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Staff, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - First NUN Protest in Washington, D.C., undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Lien Removal Surveys, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Testimonies on Plant Closings, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Revitalization of Pittsburgh and Southwestern Pennsylvania in the 1980s, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Welfare Lien Questionnaires, undated (Box 15, Folder 30-31)
  - MVUC Demonstrations Photographs, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
- Newsletters and Media, 1982-1991; IV.
  This series contains newsletters and media coverage written by and relating to the organization from 1982 to 1991. The MVUC used their newsletter, Mon News, to update their members on the services offered and as a way to recruit volunteers for their community outreach programs. The committee also ran television commercials to recruit members. The correspondences with local media and media coverage are retained in this series. This series also contains a sample of articles written about the MVUC in the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette and The Daily News. This series is arranged chronologically.
  - MVUC Logo, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter, January-February 1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Labor Notes", February 1982 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Companies Responsible for Steel Woes", March 2, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Strange Words from USW Officials", March 4, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - MVUC March 15th Rally, March 15, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
  - Reagan Protests, April 1982 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - MVUC Reporter, May 1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)